[{"question_text": "<p>The programming paradigm is ...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>a set of ideas and concepts that determine the style of writing programs, an approach to programming</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>subject to problem directions that reflect the calculation processes of information calculation and number processing</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>focuses on the accuracy and comparability of the results of scientific experiments in the field of programming and informatics presented in scientific publications</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>was formed in the study of systematic programming issues, artificial intelligence and the development of new innovative technologies in informatics</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>The programming paradigm is ...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>a set of ideas and concepts that determine the style of writing programs, an approach to programming</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>subject to problem directions that reflect the calculation processes of information calculation and number processing</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>focuses on the accuracy and comparability of the results of scientific experiments in the field of programming and informatics presented in scientific publications</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>was formed in the study of systematic programming issues, artificial intelligence and the development of new innovative technologies in informatics</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>The programming paradigm is ...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>a set of ideas and concepts that determine the style of writing computer programs</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>subject to problem directions that reflect the processes of information calculation and number processing</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>a type of declarative programming, in which writing a program consists of systematically applying one object to another</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>aimed at the accuracy and comparison of the results of scientific experiments in the field of programming and informatics presented in scientific publications</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>The word \u201cparadigm\u201d in programming...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>is used to define a family of characters that share a common method (technique) of program implementation</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>subject to problem directions that reflect the calculation processes of information calculation and number processing</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>focuses on the accuracy and comparability of the results of scientific experiments in the field of programming and informatics presented in scientific publications</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>was formed in the study of systematic programming issues, artificial intelligence and the development of new innovative technologies in informatics</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Theoretical programming is ...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>aimed at the accuracy and comparison of the results of scientific experiments in the field of programming and informatics presented in scientific publications</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>is subject to problem directions that reflect the computational processes of information calculation and number processing learned long before the advent of computers</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is a type of declarative programming, in which writing a program consists of systematically applying one object to another</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>was formed in the study of systematic programming issues, artificial intelligence and the development of new innovative technologies in informatics</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>An application programming...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>is a computer program designed to carry out a specific task other than one relating to the operation of the computer itself, typically to be used by end-users</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>aimed at the accuracy and comparison of the results of scientific experiments in the field of programming and informatics presented in scientific publications</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is a subject to problem orientations that reflect computational processes of information computation and number processing learned long before the advent of computers</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>was formed in the study of systematic programming issues, artificial intelligence and the development of new innovative technologies in informatics</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Experimental Programming \u2013</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>formed in the study of system programming issues, artificial intelligence and the development of new innovative technologies in informatics</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>is a type of declarative programming, in which writing a program consists of systematically applying one object to another</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>focuses on the accuracy and comparability of the results of scientific experiments in the field of programming and informatics presented in scientific publications</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>subject to problem orientations that reflect computational processes of information computation and number processing learned long before the advent of computers</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Programming language - ...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>is considered an official language for writing computer programs</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>usually based on combinatorial logic or \u03bb-calculus</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is a type of declarative programming, in which writing a program consists of systematically applying one object to another</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is intended to support the development of programs by obtaining results</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Computer programming is...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>the process of performing a particular computation (or more generally, accomplishing a specific computing result), usually by designing and building an executable computer program</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>usually based on combinatorial logic or \u03bb-calculus</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>divided into low-level and high-level programming languages</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>intended to support the development of programs by obtaining results</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Programming languages \u2013</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>divided into low-level and high-level programming languages</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>combine programs that solve language problems and are designed for system development</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>intended to support the development of programs by obtaining results</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>usually based on combinatorial logic or \u03bb-calculus</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Programming systems include \u2026</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>translators, library programs, editors, linker, loader and debugger</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>low-level and high-level programming languages</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>programs and software that solve language problems</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>programs designed to support the development of programs by obtaining results</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Programming Systems \u2013</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>combine programs that solve language problems and are designed for software development</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>are special service programs that can be used to service the operating system itself</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is divided into low-level and high-level programming languages</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is intended to support the development of programs by obtaining results</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Software service systems - ...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>are special service programs that can be used to service the operating system itself</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>intended to support the development of programs by obtaining results</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>combine programs that solve language problems and are designed for software development</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is divided into low-level and high-level programming languages</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Software service systems - ...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>are special service programs that can be used to service the operating system itself</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>intended to support the development of programs by obtaining results</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>combine programs that solve language problems and are designed for software development</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is divided into low-level and high-level programming languages</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>The translator...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>is a program that converts input program text in a given programming language into its equivalent output language</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>are special services that can be used to service the operating system itself</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is a program that accepts and executes the given program text at once</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is a program and is intended to support the development of programs by obtaining its results</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>A compiler ...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>is a translator, which converts the text of the given program into an object program in machine commands equivalent to it</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>are special services that can be used to service the operating system itself</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is a program that accepts and executes the given program text at once</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is a program and is intended to support the development of programs by obtaining its results</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>An interpreter ...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>is a computer program that directly executes instructions written in a programming language, without requiring them previously to have been compiled into a machine language program</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>is a translator, which converts the text of the given program into an object program in machine commands equivalent to it</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is a program that converts input program text in a given programming language into an equivalent output language</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>are special service programs that can be used to service the operating system itself</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>What functions does the compiler perform?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>translates a programming language's source code into machine code, bytecode or another programming language</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>are special service programs, with the help of which the operating system performs self-service</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is divided into low-level and high-level programming languages</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>supports the development of programs by obtaining results</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Lexical analysis is ...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>is a part of the compiler that reads the program literals and sees through them the incoming language lexemes</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>is the main part of the compiler at the analysis stage. Distinguishes the syntactic constructions of the language</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is a part of the compiler that checks the program text in terms of semantics of the incoming language</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>the program converts input program text in a given programming language into an equivalent output language</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Syntax Analysis is...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>is a second phase of the compiler design process in which the given input string is checked for the confirmation of rules and structure of the formal grammar</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>is a part of the compiler that reads the program literals and sees through them the lexemes of the incoming language</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is a part of the compiler that checks the program text in terms of semantics of the incoming language</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>the program converts input program text in a given programming language into an equivalent output language</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Semantic analysis is ...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>is a part of the compiler that checks the program text in terms of semantics of the incoming language</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>is a part of the compiler that reads the program literals and sees through them the lexemes of the incoming language</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is the main part of the compiler at the analysis stage. Distinguishes the syntactic constructions of the language</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>the program converts input program text in a given programming language into an equivalent output language</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Code Generation \u2013</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>direct generation of the resulting code - the main phase, which includes code optimization</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>actions related to the synthesis of the resulting program</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>reading data from external memory and processing them and placing them in external memory</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>there is no correct answer</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Identifier table \u2013</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>a set of data that stores information about incoming program elements</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>a set of data that stores information about actions related to the synthesis of the resulting program</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>a set of data that stores information about the last process of reading data from external memory</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>direct generation of the resulting</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>What is the life cycle of programs?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>a continuous process from the time of the decision on the need to create the program to the end of its activity</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>the time interval of the processes that the program must go through</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>program management models are called program life cycle</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>program development, assembly and integration processes</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>During the design phase of the software life cycle...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>technical task, sketches and technical projects are developed</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>formatting of the functional and information model of the object intended to be provided by the program is performed</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>programming and application testing are carried out on the basis of the software specification of the subsystems allocated at the programming stage</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>assembly and integration of the programming system, testing is carried out</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>The essence of the waterfall method -</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>the project is divided into linear sequential phases, meaning they are passed down onto each other, where each phase depends on the deliverables of the previous one and corresponds to a specialization of tasks</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>is the possibility of planning the work execution periods and the costs of the work execution</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>how to create the system, the procedures for creating it in practice, putting it into practice, and completing its activities are specified</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>determines the process of making a decision on the need to create a system</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>The advantage of the waterfall model is ...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>the possibility of planning the work execution periods and the costs of the work execution</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>there is no correct answer</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>how to create a system, determine the procedure for its creation, implementation and completion of its activities</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>there is a constant need to return to the previous steps in order to identify and revise previously made decisions</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Disadvantage of the step (waterfall) model -</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>there is a constant need to return to previous steps in order to determine and revise the decisions made earlier</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>lack of possibility to plan work completion dates and work costs</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>the project is divided into stages, and the condition for moving from one stage to the next stage is defined as the completion of all work in the previous stage</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>how to create a system, determine the procedure for its creation, implementation and completion of its activities</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Software is \u2026</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>consists of a set of programs that allow the hardware part of the system to perform the necessary actions, to \"revive\" the computer</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>consists of a set of technical tools necessary for the operation of the system</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>consists of a set of bytes necessary for the operation of the system</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>there is no correct answer</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>What are the types of software?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>system software and application software</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>functional software and application software</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>system software and structured software</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>functional software and structured software</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>The sorting algorithms are:</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>Selection sort, Bubble sort, Merge sort, Quicksort</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>Split sort, Bubble sort, Merge sort, Quicksort</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>Bubble sort, Merge sort, Split sort, Selection sort</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>Quicksort, Merge sort, Cycle sort, Split sort, Insertion sort</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>The sorting algorithms are:</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>Insertion sort, Selection sort, Bubble sort, Heap sort</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>Peer-to-peer sort, Bubble sort, Merge sort, Quicksort</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>Bubble sort, Merge sort, Split sort, Selection sort</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>Quicksort, Merge sort, Cycle sort, Split sort, Insertion sort</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>The search algorithms are:</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>linear search, binary search, jump search, exponential search</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>peer-to-peer search, linear search, binary search</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>jump search, exponential search, selection search</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>merge search, linear search, binary search, jump search</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>The search algorithms are:</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>Fibonacci search, linear search, binary search, jump search</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>peer-to-peer search, linear search, binary search</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>Fibonacci search, jump search, exponential search, selection search</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>merge search, linear search, binary search, jump search</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>The search algorithms are:</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>linear search, binary search, jump search, exponential search</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>peer-to-peer search, linear search, binary search</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>jump search, exponential search, selection search</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>merge search, linear search, binary search, jump search</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>The compiler is...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>for programming, it is an application program that controls whether the codes are typed according to the rules and outputs the result of the program</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>is an algorithm for creating a program, which controls whether the codes are typed according to the law and produces the result of the program</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is a program consisting of a sequence of actions for creating a program</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is a program consisting of a sequence of commands for creating a program</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Is it possible to use the name of one's own class as a constructor parameter?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>No</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>Yes</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>Destructor can be used as a declaration</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>Yes, only a few constructors should be declared</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>If a class doesn't have a public destructor, ...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>the default destructor is called</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>the default constructor is called</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>an error occurs</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>no change will occur</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>The program has not yet created the object, but it must use the element. What to do in this case?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>To use an element, the program must declare it as <em>public</em> and <em>static</em></p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>To use an element, the program must declare it as <em>protected</em> and <em>static</em></p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>To use an element, the program must declare it as <em>public</em> and <em>local</em></p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>To use an element, the program must declare it as <em>private</em> and <em>static</em></p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Which functions exist outside the class, and the function can refer to all areas of the class?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>Friend functions</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>Static functions</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>Inline functions</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>Constructors</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Static methods refer to ________. Complete the sentence.</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>static members</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>constructors</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>destructors</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>all members</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>When multiple constructors are declared, what should be most important?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>the number of parameters should be different</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>the type of parameters should be different</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>has nothing to do with parameters</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>there is no correct answer</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>A class that becomes a <em>friend</em> to another class _____________.</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>makes it possible to use the members of this class</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>two friend classes make it possible to use each other's members</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>must also be a friend function</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>there is no correct answer</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>A class that becomes a <em>friend</em> to another class _____________.</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>makes it possible to use the members of this class</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>two friend classes make it possible to use each other's members</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>must also be a friend function</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>there is no correct answer</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Constructors and destructors are declared in which section of the class?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>Public</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>Private</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>Protected</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>can be announced in any section</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>What is the friend function?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>a function declared with the friend class attribute, but not a member of the class</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>a function of another class that contains elements of this class among the function arguments</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>a function that is a member of the class and is declared with the friend attribute</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>a function declared as friend for a given class in another class</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>How to declare a destructor in C++?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>~Example()</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>Example()</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>~ Example</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>Example</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Which operator is used to refer to the members of an object by pointer?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>-></p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>::</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>.</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>&</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>A ________ is a special type of member function that is called automatically when an object is created.</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>constructor</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>destructor</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>friend function</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>polymorphism</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Constructor is \u2026</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>a special method that is invoked automatically at the time of object creation</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>a tool that allows you to use a single name to indicate actions specific to the classes involved</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>a tool that allows you to use methods of the same class with different names to perform the same operation</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>a tool that allows functions to be overloaded to work with different types or different arguments</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>What does <strong><em>this</em></strong> keyword mean?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>a pointer to the current object</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>a pointer to an optional object</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>a pointer to the first object</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p><strong><em>this</em></strong> is not a pointer</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>What kind of opportunity does a\u00a0<strong><em>friend</em></strong>\u00a0class provide?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>use of members of this class</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>not to use members of this class</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>delete the value in the members of this class</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>adding value to the members of this class</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Does a<strong><em> destructor</em></strong> have a parameter or a return value?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>No</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>Yes, in void type</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>Yes, in auto type</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>Yes, returns a value based on the type of the parameter</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>What type does the <strong><em>constructor</em></strong> return?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>a constructor doesn't return anything</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>auto type</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>void type</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>returns a value depending on the type of the parameter</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>When a class variable is declared as ________, the compiler makes it a single copy for objects.</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>static</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>local</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>array</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>pointer</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>_______ destroys the class objects created by constructor.</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>Destructor</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>Inline function</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>Assignment operators</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>Increment</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Is it possible to initialize objects if there is a parameterized constructor?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>Yes</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>No</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>An error occurs</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>Yes, it is necessary to refer to the object only through the pointer</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>A _____ is a user-defined data type representing a group of similar objects, which holds member functions and variables together.</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>class</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>function</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>method</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>operator</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Polymorphic class -</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>refers to a class that contains at least one virtual function</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>contains at least two virtual functions</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>if it contains at least one abstract class</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>contains at least one successor</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Is it possible to create an object of an\u00a0<strong><em>abstract class</em></strong>?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>impossible</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>it is possible</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>it is possible or not depending on the circumstances</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>there is no correct answer</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Is it possible to declare an <strong><em>abstract class</em></strong> to get a pointer or an address?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>it is possible</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>impossible</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>it is possible or not depending on the circumstances</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>there is no correct answer</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>A __________ is a function that must be overridden in a derived class and need not be defined.</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>pure virtual function</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>virtual function</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>pure function</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>virtual class</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>What is a virtual function that is not defined in the base class?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>pure virtual function</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>virtual function</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>pure function</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>such a function cannot exist</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Polymorphism is \u2026</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>all answers are correct</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>one of the most important concepts of object-oriented programming languages</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is a property using which any message could be delivered to objects of multiple classes</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>the ability of an object to take on many forms</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Types of Polymorphism in C++</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>Function overloading, Operator overloading, Function overriding, Virtual function</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>Overloading tasks, Inheriting methods, Templates</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>Inheritance of methods, Virtual functions, Templates</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>Overload functions, Inheritance, Virtual functions</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Compile time polymorphism:</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>Function overloading, Operator overloading</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>Function overriding</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>Virtual function</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>Function overriding, Virtual function</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>In OOP, ______ refers to the bundling of data with the methods that operate on that data, or the restricting of direct access to some of an object's components.</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>encapsulation</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>polymorphism</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>abstraction</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>inheritance</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Which operator cannot be overloaded in C++?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>.*</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>%=</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>&&</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>&=</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Which operator cannot be overloaded in C++?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>::</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>%=</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>|=</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>&=</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Which operator cannot be overloaded in C++?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>.*</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>%=</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>&&</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>&=</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Which operator cannot be overloaded in C++?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>.*</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>%=</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>&&</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>&=</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Which operator cannot be overloaded in C++?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>::</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>%=</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>|=</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>&=</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Where can an operator function be defined?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>can be defined both inside and outside the class definition</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>cannot be defined either in the class description or outside of it</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>can be defined only within the class definition</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>can only be defined outside the class description</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>There are two types of operator functions. What are they?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>simple and component</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>singular and even</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>single and simple</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>component and exponential</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Functional operation can be defined in three ways. What are they?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>class method, friend function and simple function</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>class copy, friend function and simple function</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>class method, virtual function and simple function</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>class method, friend function and recursive function</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Why is operator overloading necessary?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>to perform operations on objects</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>to perform operations on functions</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>to perform operations on arrays</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>to perform operations on pointers</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>What are the advantage of operator overloading?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>ability to process values \u200b\u200bof different types</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>ability to use functions in inheritance</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>using arrays as pointers</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>ability to expand the methods of creating classes</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>What is used for operator overloading?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>operator</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>function</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>class</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>struct</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>What is overloading in C++?\u200b</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>creating two or more members that have the same name but are different in number or type of parameter</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>program code for summarizing arrays</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>program code to execute pointers</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>creating two or more members that have the same type of parameter but are different in number</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Which operators cannot be overloaded in C++?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>\u201c::\u201d , \u201c.*\u201d , \u201c.\u201d , \u201c?.\u201d</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>\"&&\" , \u201c=\u201d , \u201c?\u201d , \u201c+=\u201d</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>\"cin\", \"cout\", \"for\", \"-\"</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>\"while\" , \"=\" , \"?\" , \"+=\"</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>What is a programming paradigm?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>coding principles, methods and techniques</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>a set of new programs</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>a set of accepted scientific and technical terms</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>a set of data or functions</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Encapsulation is \u2026</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>is a mechanism for combining data and the code that processes them</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>is a new way of programming to solve complex problems</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>it is possible to create a new type of data, which is easy to control</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>is a mechanism of programming based on the use of functions</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>What is used to create a class object?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>it is implemented through a special function-member known as constructor</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>it is implemented through a special function-member known as a destructor</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>it is carried out through a special function-member that allows you to save data and code from external influences</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>it is carried out through a special function-member, which provides the opportunity to create a new type of data</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>What is used to delete the class object?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>it is carried out through a special function-member known as destructor</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>it is implemented through a special function-member known as constructor</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>it is carried out through a special function-member that allows you to save data and code from external influences</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>it is carried out through a special function-member, which provides the opportunity to create a new type of data</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>How to access <strong><em>private</em></strong> data or code?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>applicable only within this object</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>it is possible to access from any part of the program</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>can be addressed through the mechanism of combining data and the code that processes them</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>can only be accessed through virtual functions and templates</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>How to access <strong><em>public</em></strong> data or code?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>can be accessed from any part of the program</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>applicable only within this object</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>can be addressed through the mechanism of combining data and the code that processes them</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>can only be accessed through virtual functions and templates</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>Inheritance is a process in which \u2026</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>one object will be able to acquire the properties of another</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>one object will be able to acquire the values \u200b\u200bof another</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>one object will be able to acquire the results of another</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>one object will be able to acquire the elements of another</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>If an object inherits its attributes from only one parent class...</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>it is called single inheritance</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>it is called batch inheritance</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>it is called virtual inheritance</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>it is called inheritance of data and functions</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>If the object inherits its attributes from several parent classes\u2026</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>it is called multiple inheritance</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>it is called single inheritance</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>it is called virtual inheritance</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>it is called inheritance of data and functions</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>How to remove the first element of a container?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>pop_front</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>pop_back</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>push_front</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>push_back</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>How to remove the last element of a container?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>pop_back</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>pop_front</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>push_front</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>push_back</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>How to add an element to the end of a container?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>push_back</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>pop_front</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>pop_back</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>push_front</p>", "is_true": false}]}, {"question_text": "<p>How to add an element to the beginning of a container?</p>", "answers": [{"answer_text": "<p>push_front</p>", "is_true": true}, {"answer_text": "<p>pop_front</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>pop_back</p>", "is_true": false}, {"answer_text": "<p>push_back</p>", "is_true": false}]}]
